# Front End / Full Stack Developer

**OWork/School Github** 

**™**Personal Github

**in**Linkedin

 ${\color{red} \, {\boxtimes} ericmcelyea@gmail.com}$ 



#### Personal statement

Hi, I am Eric McElyea. I have worked on all parts of the modern application stack. Currently I specialize in React and React Native applications. I have spent alot of time writing performant React components, writing Jest integration and snapshot tests, creating mobile applications using React Native, and optimizing performance with a deep knowledge of how React renders and the reconciler work.

Eric McElyea

## Work Experience

### Front End Developer

#### Brightidea

Worked on a very large and very old (20 years!) codebase with thousands of active users.

Add React components into backbone, PHP, and as standalone pages with navigation

Helped update old, complex, features while avoiding regressions

**Built out React Native application** 

Did more PHP than I wanted to.

May 2018 - Current

#### Solo Developer

#### **Doc Current**

This is a side project I took from nothing to production

Came up with concept, tested feasibility of idea, designed UI/UX.

Built system for uploading, editing, signing, emailing, text messaging california rental property documents

Designed and Built ReactJS application

Built React component for auto-populating, editing, signing PDF based web forms

Built NodeJS backend, designed DB

Wrote NodeJS process that converts JSON and a blank PDF to a signed, filled PDF

 $\label{prop:eq:continuous} \mbox{Handled every aspect of application development, devops, security, etc.}$ 

December 2017 - May 2018

## Full Stack Developer

#### Parsley

Worked on Front-End React, Redux application

Worked on Back-End Scala, Play Framework, Postgres

Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

### Full Stack Developer

#### Katalyst Fitness

Built front-end AngularJS application to design specs

Created scheduling system for employees, clients and studios

Created secure JWT user authorization system

Built PCI compliant credit card billing system

Created tools for automating test, build, and deploy process

Sep 2016 - Oct 2017

## Software Engineer

#### Acutulus

Work with a variety of clients who hired the company to build their software:

Tapcast - wrote android plugins for cordova/phonegap application, redid website to spec whenever it was changed (which was fairly frequently).

Tavirecruiter - Built applicant tracking system for a recruiting company

Revbooks - Creates a book of online store products, I was the new guy so I had the unenviable task of pulling online store http routes and user validation out of sites so the book could spoof a user cart/checkout experience without ever visiting the site. This did teach me alot about web fundamentals and how to interface with a plethora of different back-ends, front-ends and engineering teams.

Jan 2015 - Oct 2017

### Education

## BSc in Computer Science

#### Cal State East Bay

Relevant coursework: Data Structures, Operating Systems, Systems Programming, OOP, Web Development, Mobile Development, Data Communications and Networks, Calculus 1, 2 & 3,